# **Aaron(Yaotian) Lin**

## Frontend Developer

♀ 2 Glenti Place, Docklands VIC 3008 🖾 aaronlin74@gmail.com 📞 0420420074

https://aaron-lin-74.github.io/personal-portfolio/

### **PROFILE**

A highly motivated tech enthusiast with experience in building responsive web applications using React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express, HTML5, SASS, and CSS3. My skills include front-end web development, back-end web development, and AWS Cloud infrastructure.

Enjoy working closely with team members and customers with proven communication and customer service skills.

Passionate about learning and development with a desire to apply my knowledge, and skills to a talented engineering team to build quality applications for the users/customers.

## **TECHNIQUE SKILLS**

#### **Front End**

ReactJS 17, TypeScript 4.x, JavaScript ES6/ES7/ES8, Redux/toolkit, semantic HTML5, CSS3, Styled components, Sass, ESLint, Webpack, Babel, jQuery, AJAX, npm, yarn, Responsive Design

#### **Back End**

Node.js, Express, JWT Token, YAML, JSON, Cron

#### **Database**

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, **SQLite** 

## **Methodologies**

Agile, Scrum, Test Driven Development

## **Front End Testing**

Jest, React Testing Library

#### **Cloud services**

AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, AWS VPC, AWS Lightsail, AWS CodePipeline, Firebase

## **Develop Tools & Platforms**

Jira, Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Postman

#### **Other Languages**

Python, Bash

## **CERTIFICATES**

- AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate □
- Front End Development Libraries ☑
- Back End Development and APIs ☑

#### **EDUCATION**

03/2013 - 12/2014 **Master of Information Technology,** *University of Melbourne* Melbourne Weighted Average Mark (WAM): H1 2008 - 2012**Bachelor of Software Engineering,** ShanDong University China

### **PROJECTS**

**Learn Animals,** https://github.com/Aaron-Lin-74/learn-animal-mern-project ☑

Designed and developed a Full Stack MERN Application where kids can learn more about different kinds of animals.

- Designed and implemented the responsive, accessible web application with React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, and ESLint.
- Implemented REST API with Express, Mongoose, MongoDB Atlas, and JWT Token, which handles user authentication, fetching animal data, and subscription.
- Used AWS CodePipeline to link GitHub repository and continuously deploy to AWS Elastic Beanstalk.
- Live demo: http://learnanimalmern-env.eba-mn3hxtuv.ap-southeast-2.elasticbeanstalk.com/

## **Animal Sounds,** https://github.com/Aaron-Lin-74/how-animal-sounds ☑

Designed and implemented Animal Sounds web application using React function components and Google Firebase. It is an interactive web application where kids can hear a variety of animal sounds.

- Implemented Animal Sounds web application with React, React Router, ESLint, and Responsive Design.
- Used Firebase for user authentication, object storage, and database.
- Combined useReducer and useContext hooks to perform state management.
- Live demo: https://aaronlin-animal-sounds.web.app ☑

## **Public Chatroom,** https://github.com/Aaron-Lin-74/chatroom-project ☑

Developed a public chatroom where login users can send text messages, emojis, and photos.

- Developed the application with React, Firebase, TypeScript, React Testing Library, and ESLint.
- Fetched weather data from the third-party REST API.
- Implemented and maintained the CI/CD with GitHub Actions.
- Live demo: https://aaronlin-project-chatroom.web.app ☑

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

03/2016 - 12/2021 Melbourne

## Sales Manager, New Pathway Real Estate

- Mentored 3 team members, stepping in to support the team and deliver smooth sales processes for customers.
- Coached sales associates on product specifications, sales incentives, and selling techniques.
- Used consultative sales approach to understand customer needs and to close deals in a short period of time.
- Achieved sales goals and service targets by cultivating and securing new customer relationships.

08/2014 - 12/2014

## **Intern,** Melbourne University Press

- Melbourne
  - Gathered user requirements and designed the web application and database based on the requirement analysis.
  - Developed a forecast management web application using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, CouchDB, and Nectar cloud as the server.

12/2013 - 03/2014 Melbourne

### Intern, Peazie Social Media Group

- Involved in the Agile software development process.
- Enhanced web development skills with JavaScript, and MVC design pattern.

### **INTEREST**

- Building software in own time and learning from online sources eg:
  - AWS Skill Builder, Codecademy, FreeCodeCamp, and Udemy.
- Learning machine learning and AI from MIT OpenCourseWare and Coursera